你正被监视着
You are being watched...
政府有一套秘密的系统
The government has a secret system--
一个无时无刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我知道这些 因为这机器是我造的
I know, because I built it.
我设计这机器是用来查找恐怖活动的 但它却什么都能看到...
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror, but it sees everything...
包含普通人的暴力犯罪 像你一样的普通人
Violent crimes involving ordinary people, people like you,
政府认为不相干的犯罪
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不作出反应 所以我决定我来做
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个拍档...
But I needed a partner--
拥有干涉这一切的技术的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
被当局追捕 我们秘密行事着
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远也不会找到我们
You'll never find us.
但受害者或犯罪者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码出现的话 我们会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第14集
Person of Interest S01E14 720p HDTV x264
- 911 你有什么紧急情况? - 轮胎爆了
911. What is your emergency? Got a flat tire.
他们不肯把音乐关掉
They won't turn their music down.
我刚知道他和她睡一块去了
I just know he's sleeping with her.
请帮帮我! 是我哥
Please help me! It's my brother.
他们枪击了他 求求你 派人来吧
They shot him. Please, send someone.
不好意思 所有线路当前都很繁忙
We're sorry. All circuits are busy at this time.
没人在这
Nobody here.
我从没见你这样过
I've never seen you like this.
那个黑客肯定影响你了
That hacker must have gotten to you.
只有偏执狂才能生存 明智的建议
Only the paranoid survive-- Sage advice.
我要从头开始重建整个系统
Well, I'll need to rebuild all my systems from scratch,
加强防火墙
reinforce the firewall.
- 我能帮忙吗? - 可以
Anything I can do? Yes.
新号码
New number...
- 今早刚出现 - 图书馆崩了也有?
Just came in this morning. Even with the library offline?
他叫Darren McGrady 14岁
His name is Darren McGrady, 14 years old.
那是最后的已知地址 你最好开始行动了
That's his last known address. You better get started.
嘿 Finch...
Hey, Finch...
你的机器出号码会不会慢了几天?
Any chance your machine gave us the number a few days late?
不会 怎么?
No. Why?
因为我要爬过警方的警戒线 才能进入Darren的公寓
Because I had to crawl through police tape to get inside Darren's apartment.
图书馆也许暴露了 但我可以保证机器没有
The library may have been compromised, but I can assure you that the machine was not.
不管发生什么
Whatever happened there,
Darren肯定正出事着
Darren's situation must be ongoing.
好像是私闯民宅
Looks like a home invasion.
地上的血是谁的?
So whose blood is on the floor?
嘿 你是谁?
Hey. Who are you?
Stills探员
Detective Stills.
- 你是管理人? - 没错
- You the super? - That's right.
- 现在查案太晚了吧? - 不介意告诉我这里发生什么吧?
A little late for the party, aren't you? Mind telling me what happened here?
好像是 其中一个房客被枪杀了
What it looks like-- One of my tenants got shot...
大概一周前 大的那个 Travis McGrady
About a week ago. Older kid-- Travis McGrady.
太可惜了 他交租很准时
Damn shame. Real good about paying rent on time.
Travis有个弟弟 叫Darren
Travis had a younger brother, Darren.
- 他怎么了? - 我不知道
- What happened to him? - I don't know.
他被警察带走
Cops took him with them.
嘿 我什么时候可以清理这里 让新房客入住?
Hey, when can I clean this place up and get a new tenant in here?
早上好探员 想我了?
Morning, Detective. Miss me?
我总是想象你
You know, I always pictured you
出现在我的车后...戴着手铐
in the back of my car... In handcuffs.
求同存异吧
Well, to each his own.
- 拿到档案了吗? - Travis McGrady
Any luck pulling that file? Travis McGrady--
胸部近距离被射中两枪
Took two shots to the chest, point blank.
有人看到三名黑人男性逃离现场
Three black males were seen fleeing the building.
他弟弟怎样 Darren?
What about the brother, Darren?
正好案发后回家 发现Travis失血过多
Came home right after it happened, found Travis bleeding out.
这里记录他拨打911了
Says here he called 911.
是 花了半小时才有人出警
Yeah, it took half an hour for first responders to show up.
- Travis已经死亡 - 父母怎么了?
Travis was already dead. What happened to the parents?
父亲不详 母亲三年前死于肾衰竭
No father in the picture. Mother died of renal failure three years ago,
所以Travis是Darren的合法监护人
so Travis was Darren's legal guardian.
现在他无依无靠了
Now he's got nobody.
- 知道他现在在哪吗? - 失踪
Any idea where he is now? Missing.
那孩子在分局等儿童保护机构等了一整晚
Kid waited all night at the precinct for Child Services.
看他们没来 他起身就走了
When they didn't show up, he just up and walked out.
我要追踪他...
I need to track him down...
- 要快 - 嘿
- Fast. - Hey.
不告诉我你和你朋友 是怎样挑选要追踪的人的?
You ever gonna tell me exactly how you and your friend pick the people you're chasing?
好的 我会和负责的探员谈
All right. I'll talk to the detective assigned on the case,
看看有没有报告漏掉的信息
see if there's anything he left out of that report.
比如他是怎样把孩子弄丢了
Like how he lost the kid.
凶案调查组怎么想介入Crown高地的枪杀案?
Since when does a homicide task force want in on a shooting in Crown Heights?
你没有更重要的活干吗
Don't you have something more high profile to work--
比如老拿枪打别人膝盖那家伙?
Like that guy who's kneecapping everybody?
上头想绩效数字好看点
Chief of "D"s wants to polish compstat numbers--
命令我们去调查任何悬案
Ordered us to climb on any open cases.
好吧 是这样的
Okay. It goes like this.
上周五受害者在工作...
Last Friday the victim was working at the--
Travis 对吧? 他叫Travis
Travis, right? His name is Travis.
- 没错 - 嗯 这个Travis
Right. Well, this Travis--
他在Thighs&Fries上夜班
He's working the late shift at the Thighs & Fries.
因为一个女服务员而与三名男性发生争吵
Got into an altercation with three males over some waitress.
有人嘴巴不干净 Travis上去揍他 打到脱臼
Somebody got frisky, Travis went at him, tossed him out the joint.
也就是之后被看到逃离现场的三人
Same three guys seen later fleeing his apartment building.
我发现他们离开餐馆后 尾随Travis回家
I figure they left the restaurant. They followed Travis on his way home from work.
其它的你都知道了
You know the rest.
他弟弟说 他们拿走了他的工作帽
The little brother-- He said, uh, they took his work hat.
有三个嫌疑人的线索吗?
Any leads on the three suspects?
- 服务员有给出描述什么的吗? - 在那个街区?
Waitress give a description, anything? In that neighborhood?
你说笑呢? 没人敢供出那些暴徒的
Are you kidding? Ain't nobody gonna dime out those thugs.
找弟弟Darren有进展了吗?
Any progress on finding the little brother, Darren?
- 我哪有精力去找坐不住的孩子啊 - 那当然
I don't have time to chase after every kid - who can't sit still. - Of course not.
我找到他时
When I find him,
我会告诉他你帮了大忙
I'll let him know you were a big help.
好像Darren他哥惹错人了
Sounds like Darren's brother picked a fight with the wrong crowd.
如果他们认为Darren在那晚看到了什么 接下来会让他永远出不了声
If they think Darren saw anything that night, they'll be looking to silence him next.
所以Darren在哪枪手是谁 我们都毫无头绪
So we don't have a clue where Darren is or who the shooters are.
目击证人可以指证枪手 他们只是太害怕
Witnesses can ID the shooters. They're just too scared.
他们怎么会对你开口?
Why would they want to talk to you?
我自有办法
I have my ways.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
Lisa?
不好意思 我要迟到了
Sorry. I'm running late for something.
而且我已经把所知的关于Travis 和那些人的全部告诉给警察了
Besides, I already told the police everything I know about Travis and those guys.
我不是警察
I'm not a cop.
我在找Darren McGrady Travis的弟弟
I'm looking for Darren McGrady, Travis' little brother.
- 对不起 我帮不了你 - 你知道你害怕...
I'm sorry. I can't help you. I know you're afraid...
我相信Travis为你挺身而出
Just like I'm sure Travis was scared
对抗那群暴徒时也很害怕
when he stuck up for you against those thugs.
但他还是做到了
But he did it anyway.
那些人一直来白吃白喝 大喊大叫
Those guys come in there all the time, grabbing and hollering.
我真不知道他是怎么想的
I don't know what the hell he was thinking.
他关心你
He cared for you...
就像关心他的弟弟 Darren
Just like he cared for his little brother, Darren.
杀死Travis的人可能正在追杀Darren
The guys that killed Travis may be coming after Darren now.
我要你帮忙找到他们
I need your help tracking them down.
- 听着 我想帮忙 但是... - 你不用说出名字
Look, I want to help, but-- You don't have to give me a name.
帮我指对路就行
Just point me in the right direction.
你这种从暗处出现的人 追缉坏人
Guy like you, coming out of the shadows, looking for bad guys,
很适合去漫画书店
you'd fit right in at the comic book store...
过几个街区
Couple blocks that way.
他们在那聚集
They hang out there.
谢谢
Thanks.
好的 孩子 免费漫画 给你一本
Okay, kids, free comics. There you go-- One for you.
不错吧? 嘿 很高兴再见到你
How about that? Hey. Good to see you again.
好 向你妈妈问好
All right. Say hi to your mom.
Wilcox先生 这兄弟的超能力是什么?
Mr. Wilcox, what's this dude's superpower?
没有服装 披肩
He got no costume, no cape.
因为做超级英雄不用任何披肩或斗篷
'Cause being a superhero is not about a cape or a cowl.
而是要保护自己的同伴
It's about protecting your fellow man,
在别人无能为力时照看他
looking out for him when no one else will.
看看细节
Look at the detail on that.
呃...打扰
Uh... Excuse you.
嘿 Carter 我可能找到其中一个枪手
Hey, Carter, I may have found one of our shooters--
在Crown街和Albany路的拐角 往南走了
Corner of Crown and Albany, headed south.
两分钟路程 就到
I'm two minutes away, be right there.
Finch 我看到Darren了
Finch, I got eyes on Darren.
他安全吗 Reese先生?
Is he safe, Mr. Reese?
- 安全不了多久 - 嘿 哟 Brick
- Not for long. - Hey, yo, Brick.
把帽子拿下来
Take off that hat.
你以为在和谁说话呢 矮子?
Who do you think you're talking to, shorty?
其中一个杀死我哥的懦弱混蛋
One of the spineless punks that killed my brother--
在我们家里射死他的
Shot him dead in our home.
要我教你怎么用吗 小家伙?
Want me to show you how to use that thing, little man?
干什么呢 哥们? 放开我
What the hell you doing, man? Get off of me.
这白痴要完蛋了
This fool is as good as dead.
- 哟 - 我可不会射偏
- Yo... - I won't miss.
- 拿回来! - 把手机放下
- Give that back! - Drop your phone.
放开我 哥们 嘿 别担心哥们 这事没完
Get off me, man. Hey, don't worry, man. This ain't over.
我要杀死你 还有其他同伙
I'ma kill you and the rest of your crew.
走着瞧 我的弟兄会找到你的
Yeah, we'll see about that. My boys will be looking for you.
- 我看到你又在交友了 - 找到失踪孩子
I see you made friends as usual. Found our missing kid.
现在我要带走他 这个是谋杀嫌疑人
Now I got to get him out of here. He's your murder suspect.
趴地上
Get down on the ground.
现在双手抱头
Put your hands behind your head now.
你去哪?
Where you going?
带他去安全的地方 不好意思
Got to get him somewhere safe. Sorry.
所有单位 请回应
All units, please respond
Crown街附近有枪声
to shots fired in the vicinity of Crown and--
还不知道警察可以选择接哪个报案呢
Didn't know cops could pick and choose which calls to answer.
没说过我是警察
Never said I was a cop.
那你是什么?
So what are you, then?
这些日子我自己也在想
One of these days I'll have to come up with a good answer for that one.
地摊货的话 还算挺不错
It's a nice piece, considering you bought it off the street.
- 哪里来的钱? - 把电视典当了 卖点东西
Where'd you get the cash? Pawned a TV, sold some stuff.
看到你有吹小号 那个也给当了吧
Saw you play the trumpet. I'm guessing you pawned that too.
- 有特长吗? - 你觉得呢?
- You any good? - What do you think?
我哥想让我去音乐学校...
My brother wanted me to go to music school...
不用惹上那群流氓
Instead of getting mixed up with the thugs.
看看现在 惹上那群流氓了
And here you are, mixed up with the thugs.
你跟踪那个叫Brick的小子
So you tracked down that Brick kid.
你认为你哥会希望你这么做?
You think that's what your brother would have wanted you to do?
看他戴着那顶帽子 好像是战利品一样
Saw him wearing that hat like it was some type of scalp.
- 这是不对的 - 我来搞定
It wasn't right. I'll take care of it.
你?
You?
怎么搞?
How?
等等 我们去哪?
Wait a minute. Where we going?
Youth Support Group Home
Darren 这是Fusco探员
Darren, this is Detective Fusco.
他是一个...朋友
He's a...Friend.
- 这人? - 是的
- This guy? - Yep.
噢 门都没有
Oh, hell, no.
- 有什么不满 矮子? - 你就是一坏警察
What's your problem, half pint? You're a dirty cop all day long.
好 听着...
All right, look...
首先你让我调查我们的共同朋友
First you got me investigating our mutual friend.
现在我要照顾这个没大没小的小混球?
Now I got to babysit this disrespectful punk?
我有工作的 Carter会问起更多问题
I have a day job. Carter's gonna start asking a lot more questions.
Carter交给我处理 这里安全吗?
You leave Carter to me. Now, is this place safe?
是 她喜欢帮助孩子 讨厌文书工作
Yeah. She likes to help kids. She hates paperwork.
- 她一向都收离家少年的 - 我没离家出走
She takes in strays all the time. I'm not a stray.
- 他在这很安全 - 好
- He'll be safe here. - Good.
我还会回来 在那之前 看住他
I'll be back, but until then, he doesn't leave your sight.
- 哟 你真要把我丢这? - 很快回来
Yo, you really gonna leave me here? Not for long.
要还车
Got to return a vehicle.
Brick
Brick.
运气不好
Bad luck.
你戴着死人的帽子招摇过市
You walking around wearing a dead guy's hat.
从哪里搞到的?
Where'd you get it?
- 找到的 - 在哪?
- Found it. - Where?
在街上 挺适合的
In the street. I like the way it fit.
是啊 帽子正在实验室里
Yeah, well, that hat is in the lab right now.
DNA总能道出真相
DNA always tells the truth.
从你这听来对我们都好
Better for both of us if I heard it from you.
要花三个月时间拿到结果 所以要不我们在这舒服
It takes three months to get those results back, so either we're gonna get cozy in here,
要不你现在就把电话给我
or you can just give me my phone call now.
没电话了 削减经费啊
Phone's busted-- Budget cuts.
- 你也明白的 - 随便吧
- You know how these things go. - Whatever.
- 没法指控我 你就不能关着我 - 是啊 没错
You can't hold me if you can't charge me. Yeah, that's right.
老手了吧? 有一件事你说对了
You've done all this before, right? Yeah, well, you're right about one thing.
我能指控你了...你才出得了这里
You'll get out of here... When I take you to your arraignment.
你正在试图联系你的朋友Brick
You're trying to reach your friend Brick.
你好 Curtis
Hello, Curtis.
(一切如常啊 怎么停下来了?)
Business as usual.What's the hold up?
好车 信封里的钱
Nice cars, cash in envelopes--
这些人不是街头暴徒 Finch
These guys aren't street thugs, Finch.
他们有组织 有办法查车牌么?
They've got some kind of operation. Any way to run the plates?
我还在重建驱动 得让硬件运行
I'm still rebuilding the drives. Had to make a hardware run.
如果一切顺利 要过几小时吧
If all goes well, we're looking at a couple of hours.
好 我跟Fusco警探说说
Good. I'll check with Detective Fusco.
一切都好么 Finch?
Is everything all right, Finch?
还好 Reese先生
Just fine, Mr. Reese.
Wren先生 有个人来见你 一位Ingram先生
Mr. Wren, a man is here to see you-- A Mr. Ingram.
当然 请带他进来
Of course. Bring him in, please.
Will 你好吗?
Will. How are you?
我很好 Harold叔叔
I'm well, Uncle Harold.
显然 你也一样
As are you, evidently.
- 想必生意兴隆吧 - 很高兴 确实是
- Business must be booming. - Happily, yes.
在保险这行 坏事出得越少
In the insurance business, the fewer bad things that happen in the universe,
我们钱赚得越多
the more money we make.
- 等我把这点事处理完 我们去吃午饭 - 慢慢来
Let me tie up a few loose ends, and then we'll go to lunch. Take your time.
- 我基本整理完父亲的遗物了 - 有啥发现么?
I almost finished sorting through all dad's stuff. Find anything interesting?
有一两样东西 我相信他想给你
One or two things I'm sure he would have wanted you to have.
多数是些无聊物
Mostly it was boring stuff,
除了... 除了这个
except-- except for this,
有点诡异
which is just strange.
"第一天 那台机器 2005年2月24日"
"Day one: The machine, February 24, 2005."
- 很有趣 不是么? - 是么?
It's interesting, isn't it? Is it?
我跟你说过我在研究父亲关停公司那段时期
I told you I'm looking into that period when dad shut down operations at the company.
这正好在那段时期 显然他在庆祝些什么 但究竟是什么?
This is right in the middle of that. Now, obviously he was celebrating something, but what?
某机器? 这机器?
A machine? The machine?
不晓得 你爸你懂的
I wouldn't know. You know your dad--
- 一有借口就香槟庆祝 - 我猜你说得对
- Any excuse for champagne. - Well, I guess you're right.
但我想到还有个人可能知道
But there's still one person who I think of who might know.
你可能也认识她...
You probably know her too...
Alicia Corwin?
不 觉得不认识
No. I don't think so.
在那七年空白的所有档案中只出现过她的名字 而她还为白宫工作
Hers is the only name that appears in any of the files during that seven-year blackout, and she worked for the White House.
我猜他们为某些事有所接触
I guess they were in touch about something.
- 你跟她联系过么? - 挺不容易的
Have you been in contact with her? It wasn't easy.
父亲死后 她在一年前辞掉了政府工作
After she quit her job at the government a year ago after dad died,
她搬到了西弗吉尼亚一个偏僻小镇 绿岸
she moved to this remote town in West Virginia-- Green Bank.
- 从没听说过 - 我也没
- Never heard of it. - Me neither.
结果这是美国唯一一个
Turns out it's the only place in the US.
没有手机或无线网络的地方
That doesn't have cell phones or wireless Internet.
显然他们处理了射电望远镜
Apparently, they do something to the radio telescopes.
- 你确定你不是捕风捉影么 Will? - 或许吧 除了一点
Are you sure you're not chasing shadows here, Will? Maybe, except for one thing.
还记得父亲与政府签的那个一美元合同么?
Remember that contract that dad signed with the government for $1?
就在第二天 2005年2月25日
It's the next day-- February 25th, 2005.
哇 确实可疑
Well, that is something.
我弄好了 也饿了
I'm finished here, and I'm starving.
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
Fusco探员
Detective Fusco.
开玩笑么 啥时候?
You're kidding me. When?
- 你好 Lionel - 嘿 我刚接到教养院的电话
Hello, Lionel. Hey, I just got a call from the group home.
Darren失踪了
Darren's missing.
- 你这啥意思? 我叫你盯住他 - 我每小时查他岗啊
What do you mean? I told you to check on him. I've been checking on him every hour.
你以为他们为啥打电话给我? 那孩子肯定是走出去了
Why do you think they called me? Kid must have just walked out.
孩子有那样做的习惯
Kid's got a habit of doing that.
那好 说一句 这不是我的错
Yeah, well, just for the record, this is not my fault.
为你当私家侦探 忙不过来
Too busy playing private investigator for you.
- 结果呢? - 有趣
- And how's that going? - Interesting.
有新消息会告诉你 我们要拿这孩子怎么办?
I'll tell you when I know more. What are we gonna do about this kid?
我猜我知道他可能去的地方
I think I know where he might be headed.
Ferdy's Bur
哟 喝啤酒的...
Yo, Hops & Barley...
我在找两个废物
Looking for a couple punks--
Curtis和Trim 你们认识他们不?
Curtis and Trim. You know 'em?
- 说啥? - 你听到我说的了
- Say what? - You heard me--
Curtis和Trim 我直呼他们名字
Curtis and Trim. I'm calling 'em out.
你是在找死么 好斗小子?
You trying to get yourself killed, Scrappy Doo?
你快让我不耐烦了 你也许怕他们 但我不怕
You're beginning to wear my last nerve. You might be scared of 'em, but I'm not.
你个侏儒快被扔出门了
You about to get yourself tossed, dwarf.
除非你愿意听他的
Not unless you care to follow him.
放这孩子走如何?
Why not let the kid go?
要是我不呢?
And if I don't?
Oh, boom!
哟 那是真格的少林和武当神功
Yo, now, that was some straight-up Shaolin and wu-tang whup-ass.
那是什么搏击术啊?
What kind of fighting style is that?
你是个聪明有天分的孩子 Darren
You're a smart, talented kid, Darren.
你要向我保证 别去找这些人了
You got to promise me that you'll stop looking for these guys.
你在外头太危险了
It's too dangerous for you out there.
这是啥?
What's this?
我只剩这些了
It's all I got left.
我想雇你帮我消灭那些害死我哥哥的人
I want to hire you to help me take down those guys who killed my brother.
假设我不是警察 而是职业杀手 是这意思么?
So, if I'm not a cop, I'm a mercenary, is that it?
不 我判断出来了 你是个浪人
No, I figured it out. You're a ronin.
- 浪人? - 对 浪人
A ronin? Yeah, a ronin.
就是 就是没有主人的武士
It's like-- It's like a samurai with no master.
严格来说 你该剖腹
Technically, you should have killed yourself.
那是规则
That's the code.
但你选择云游四方
But instead you're out wandering the land,
救苦救难
helping people.
- 所以现在我雇你帮我 - 我不受雇
So now I'm paying you to help me. I'm not for hire.
你不能阻止我找他们
You can't stop me from going after them.
但我有你在旁胜算更大
But I have a better chance with you there.
没办法说服你低调点 哈?
There's no way to convince you to just lie low, huh?
你把钱留着吧
You can keep your money.
别 伙计 收下
Nah, man. Take it.
- 就算正式成交了 - 不
- It makes it official. - No.
如果我们要做这件事 就得按我的方法来
If we're gonna do this, we're gonna do it my way.
意味着不杀人
That means no killing.
这是我的现行收费标准
This is my going rate.
好吧 伙计 成交
All right, man, deal.
你现在为我工作 我该知道你名字
Look, you're working for me now. I ought to know your name.
呃 你可以叫我...
Uh, you can call me..
Reese
Reese.
他在干嘛?
What's he doing, man?
- 喂 喂 嘿! 你们这么脏 别靠近我的干净车 - 我的错! 我的错!
Yo, yo, hey! Keep your dirty ass - away from my clean car. - My bad! My bad!
喂 我不是雇你坐在这儿看戏的
I didn't hire you to just sit here and watch.
我们什么时候打倒他们?
When are we gonna take them down?
我们已经开始了 第一步 观察
We've already started. Step one-- Observe.
最快输掉战斗的方式 就是不了解对手而贸然行动
The most efficient way to lose a fight is to act without knowing your enemy.
你好 交钱日 老伙计
Payday, old man.
- 全交了 300块 - 那是保护费
It's all there-- $300. That's protection.
- 其他的呢? - 行行好 伙计们
- Where's the rest? - Oh, come on, guys.
如果州府发现我在卖那些票 我会失去合法彩票生意
If the state found out I was selling those tickets, I'd lose my legit lottery business.
彩票?
Tickets?
对 他们通过当地店主卖私彩
Yeah, they're running numbers through local shop owners,
但他们拿走所有钱 不缴税
but they take all the money, tax-free.
警察知不知道 还是根本不关心?
The cops know about this, or they just don't care?
多半分了警察一份 让他们睁只眼闭只眼
Probably giving them a cut to turn a blind eye.
你没交够钱 Andre 你的损失会多得多
You short Andre, you'll lose a lot more.
- 谁是Andre? - 不认识
- Who's Andre? - I don't know.
警察放任这些家伙为所欲为
Man, these cops let these guys do whatever they want--
杀了我哥哥 横行乡里无所顾忌
Kill my brother, walk around like they can't be touched.
但现在我们知道 他们怎么赚钱了
But now we know how they're making their money.
他们的弱点暴露出来了
So they just got a lot less untouchable.
啊 "观察"
Ah... "Observe."
实话说 我一直讨厌观察 你等着
To tell you the truth, I've always hated observing.
你快付钱 否则有你好看
Wait here. You paying up, or we got a problem?
赶紧 老头
Hurry up, pops.
只剩几家了 伙计 我们快完成了
Just a couple more to go, man, we'll be good.
喂! 噢哇!
Yo! Oh, whoa!
那是我的车!
That's my car!
那是第二步 娃
That was step two, kid.
在Rutland路和52街路口会合
Meet me at the corner of Rutland and 52nd.
嘿 咋了伙计? Trim的车在哪?
Hey, what's up, man? Where's Trim's car?
策略性储存了
Strategically stored.
我要敲山震虎... 看有啥秘密泄露
I just needed to shake 'em up a bit... See what comes loose.
酷 酷
Cool, cool.
- 我需要他们手机的卫星定位 - 等下
I need GPS on their cell. Just a minute.
我不太支持你和小Darren的麻烦安排
I'm not sure I'm in favor of your troubling arrangement with young Darren.
我也对我们的麻烦安排心存疑虑
I'm not sure I'm in favor of our troubling arrangement,
特别是在你去处理神秘事务而失踪时
especially when you disappear on mysterious business.
卫星定位在找了 Reese先生
GPS is up, Mr. Reese.
- 你在跟谁讲话? - 技术支援 来吧
Who are you talking to? Tech support. Come on.
嘿 你杀过人么?
Hey, you ever kill anyone?
杀过
Yes.
他们是坏人么?
Were they bad?
有些...不全是
Some...
有些?
Not all. Some?
所以说你主人骗了你
That means your master tricked you,
命令你去杀其实不坏的人
told you to kill bad people that really weren't.
很多浪人都是这种命
A lot of ronin ended up that way.
知道我怎么想么 T? 我想你的车没了
You know what I think, T? I think your ride's gone, yo.
- 闭嘴 Curtis - 那...第三步?
Shut up, Curtis. So...Step three?
把你的意志强加于敌人 直捣他们弱点
To impose your will on your enemy, make for their weak points.
啊 在讲战争艺术
Oh. Talking art of war.
你读《孙子兵法》?
You read Sun Tzu?
当然咯 伙计 所有武士都知道孙子
Of course, man. All samurai know Sun Tzu.
行了 伙计
Come on, man.
弄辆新车 打电话理赔
Just get a new car. Call for the insurance.
啥理赔?
What insurance?
偷车的时候你和我在一起
You were with me when I stole the damn thing.
对 但你买了那些轮框 他们可以赔那些
Yeah, but you bought those rims. They might replace those.
- 你个蠢货站起来 - 冷静 伙计!
Get your dumb ass up, man. Chill, man!
去把你祖母的Beater开来 在Andre的店和我会合
Go get your grandma's beater and meet me at Andre's.
今晚要收很多钱
Big money run tonight. Steps four and five--
第四第五步 找到幕后指使 找出打击他的办法 来吧
Find the boss and figure out how to hurt him. Come on.
你关押的那个火爆小子犯啥事了?
What's the story on that banger you're holding?
- 能起诉了么? - 他是一起枪击案的涉案人
You got a charge yet? His name came up in a shooting.
我在等一组照片
I'm just waiting for a photo packet.
明天之前我们都可控告他 队长
We have until tomorrow to arraign him, captain.
- 我仍在收集证据 - 快没时间了 Carter
- I'm still collecting evidence. - You're reaching, Carter.
如果那孩子5点前没被控告 我希望你把他放了
If that kid's not arraigned by 5:00, I want you to kick him.
喂 Reese 那是Trim
Yo, Reese, there's Trim.
- 他在这边干嘛? - 现在 记住 重点不是超能力
What's he doing back here? Now, remember, it's not about the superpowers.
而在于谁保护你 让你安全
It's about who protects you and who keeps you safe.
回家去
Go on home.
天 他们也让Wilcox先生卖这些彩票?
Man, they got Mr. Wilcox selling those tickets too?
恐怕没这么简单
I'm not sure it's that simple.
你们来晚了
You're late.
车出了点问题 Andre
Had a little car trouble, Andre.
- 那是Andre? - 爬得越高
That's Andre? The higher up you go,
越难分辨好人和坏人
the harder it gets to tell the good guys from the bad.
- 警方还关押着Brick? - Brick的事我来处理
Police still got Brick? Let me worry about Brick.
你们开来的Beater咋回事?
What's with the beater you rolled up in?
呃 是我祖母的
Uh, it's my grandma's.
- 你们运我的五十万 要用那辆... - 那就是我们开那辆车的原因 Andre
You're gonna move half a million dollars of my money - in that piece-- - That's why we got it, Andre--
换辆车 换条路线 以策安全
Switching up the cars, switching up the routes, just to be safe.
我仍然一眼看出你在撒谎
I still smell you lying a mile away.
不 是真话 自从警察抓了Brick 我们想也许...
No, for real. Since the cops got Brick, we thought maybe--
你们不必操心Brick 你们只需操心我
You don't need to worry about Brick. All you need to do is worry about me.
做我叫你们做的 拿给我我想要的
Do whatever I tell you to do, get me whatever I want, and right now
而现在 我想今晚把我的钱运到布莱顿海滩
I want my damn money in Brighton Beach tonight.
要是搞砸这事 我定会杀了你们
Now y'all mess that up, and I'm gonna kill you both.
现在我们知道谁弱小 谁掌权
Now we know who's weak, who's in charge,
以及怎么打击他 第六步是什么 伙计?
and how to hurt him. What's step six, man?
那是好玩的部分 来吧
Well, that's the fun part. Come on.
- 你觉得Brick会招供么? - Brick挺得住
Yo, you think Brick's gonna talk? Brick is cool.
Andre会保护他
Andre will protect him.
Andre会照顾我们所有人 只要我们帮他做事
Andre will take care of all of us, as long as we take care of him.
Trim 那不是你的车么?
Trim, ain't that your ride?
你的车找到了
Found your car.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
这可不是你睡觉的地方 哥们
Wrong place to sleep it off, buddy.
你和我需要谈谈
You and I need to talk.
- 我忙着呢 Carter - 我听说你出了个小车祸
In the middle of something, Carter. I heard about your little traffic accident.
你把那孩子卷进去干什么?
What have you gotten that kid mixed up in?
- 别担心 他不在车里 - 那孩子是未成年人
Don't worry. He wasn't in the car. That boy is a minor.
- 你要对他的人身安全负责任 - Brick还在你手里?
You're responsible for his welfare. You still have Brick?
嗯 Womack以为我今天早上把他放了呢
Yeah, Womack thinks I released him this morning.
昨天晚上你撞的那个人呢?
What about that other guy you slammed into last night?
他会告诉我们Travis McGrady谋杀案的情况的
He's about to debrief us on Travis McGrady's murder.
要是你愿意 喊破喉咙都没关系
You can scream if you want.
去你丫的
Kiss my ass.
- 你把枪扔哪了? - 什么枪?
Where'd you dump the gun? What gun?
你杀Travis McGrady用的那把枪
The gun you used to kill Travis McGrady.
Travis什么?
Travis who?
这钱本该送到布莱顿海滩
This money is supposed to be in Brighton Beach.
问题是... 它现在跟你在Crown高地
Trouble is... It's here with you in Crown Heights.
Andre会杀了你的
Andre's gonna kill you.
你真认为Andre会相信你的话?
Do you really think Andre would believe your story?
如果我是Andre 我会认为你偷走了所有的钱
If I were Andre, I'd assume you stole every dime.
我会派人把钱找到
I'd send people in to find it,
然后干掉你
then kill you.
所以你活命的唯一办法
So the only way you're gonna survive
就是你带着钱一分不少地回去
is if you come back with every last dime.
是谁杀了Travis McGrady?
So who killed Travis McGrady?
现在你的命可是值50万
Right now your life is worth a half a million dollars.
两万块...
$20,000 of it...
就这么化为青烟了
Up in smoke.
枪在哪 Curtis?
Where's the gun, Curtis?
五万块化为青烟了
$50,000 of your life up in smoke.
Andre会相信我的
Andre's gonna believe me.
我们走着瞧
Let's find out.
什么? 不! 住手 住手 住手!
What? No! Stop, stop, stop!
杀人凶器在哪呢?
Where's the murder weapon?
烟囱...
Chimney...
我奶奶的房子那
Top of my grandma's building.
最好在那里
It better be.
- 你好 Will 好久不见 - 谢谢你能见我 Alicia
Hello, Will. Long time. Thanks for meeting me, Alicia.
我们要不找间咖啡店或者酒吧...
Maybe we should go to a cafe or bar--
- 找个暖和点的地方 - 如果你不介意 我更愿意在外面谈
Somewhere warm. If you don't mind, I prefer it outside.
很抱歉我没能参加你父亲的葬礼
I'm so sorry I couldn't make your father's funeral.
我真的很想到场
I really wanted to be there.
只不过那段时间对我来说太困难了
It was just a difficult time for me.
- 他人那么好 - 我只是希望我能多了解他一些
He was such a lovely man. I just wish I'd known him better.
给
Here.
这是我想见你的原因 我在他的遗物里发现了这个
That's why I wanted to meet you. I found it in his things.
我想知道你对此知道些什么
I wondered if you knew anything about it.
他第二天跟政府签了一份价值一美元的合同
Well, he signed a contract with the government the next day for $1.
- 什么合同? - 我不知道 上面只写了 "服务"
For what? I don't know. It just said "services."
但我很肯定这和
But I'm pretty sure that it had something to do
IFT要倒闭时 他的工作有关
with the work he was doing at IFT while they were closed.
我希望你能告诉我
I was hoping you could tell me.
你真的确定你想要知道吗?
Are you really sure you want to know?
是的 我想知道
Yes, I do.
IFT当时快倒闭了 你爸爸的投资不尽人意
IFT was about to fail. Your dad's investments had backfired.
他的研发部门好几年都没出什么成果
His R&D had produced nothing for years.
他向我寻求帮助
He came to me for help.
我说服政府帮他渡过难关
I persuaded the government to bail him out
用IFT的几个专利作为条件
in exchange for some of IFT's patents.
就是这么回事? 一美元买爸爸的专利?
That's what this is about-- A dollar for dad's patents?
- 我想是这样的 - 所以这是政府在帮他
I'm afraid so. So this is about the government helping him
或是毁他 可为什么要喝香槟呢?
or screwing him, but why drink champagne?
"那台机器"又是什么意思呢?
And what does it mean-- "The machine"?
是被机器压垮了的意思吗?
Crushed by the machine?
我想是的 在某种程度上
I suppose, yes, in a way,
他被机器压垮了...
he was crushed by the machine--
先后经历了离婚 公司倒闭
Going through a divorce, his company collapsing.
你爸爸那时非常痛苦
Your dad was in a dark place.
我知道想到他最后的日子是这个样子的 一定很难受
I know it must be tough to think of his final days that way,
但放手吧 Will
but let it go, Will.
你的话和Harold叔叔如出一辙
You sound just like my Uncle Harold.
是吗? 他是谁?
I do? Who's he?
我爸爸最好的朋友... Harold Wren
My dad's best friend-- Harold Wren.
你确定你俩从没见过面吗?
Are you sure you two never met?
没有
No.
我们没见过 我得走了
We haven't. I have to go.
抱歉我帮不上你什么忙了
I'm sorry I couldn't be more help.
我的货被人截了 队长
My delivery was intercepted, captain.
我的两个手下和布莱顿海滩的五十万都不见了
I'm missing two couriers and half a million dollars in Brighton Beach money.
我需要你的帮助
Okay, I need your help.
- 你这次得自己摆平这事了 - 这超出我能力范围了啊
You're on your own with this one. This was out of my control.
不可抗力不在我们的保护范围之内
Force majeure is not covered by our protection.
我们的合伙人把这次失败都怪罪在你头上了
Our associates blame you for this debacle.
搞定这事... 赶紧的
Fix it...Fast.
好吧 我会搞定这事的...
All right, I'll handle this...
- 靠我自己 - 我对你的成功很有信心
On my own. I'm confident in your success.
但我需要你帮我个忙
I need something from you.
我的人Brick
My employee Brick is being held
被你们的人无缘无故地关起来了 我要你把他弄出来...
by your people without a charge, okay? I need you to get him out...
除非这也不在你们的保护范围之内
Unless that's not covered by your protection.
我会尽力的
I'll see what I can do.
你好吗 警探?
How are you, Detective?
他是你的朋友?
That's a friend of yours?
是的
Yeah.
Carter 你还羁押着那个嫌疑人?
Carter, you still have that suspect in holding?
- 我刚要放他走来着 - 你好几个小时前就应该那么做了
I was just about to let him go. You should have done that hours ago.
这么做可不明智 警探 现在就把嫌疑人给我放了
Not a bright move, Detective. Release the suspect now.
抱歉我之前以为你是警察呢
Sorry I thought you were a cop.
警察本身并没什么错...
Nothing wrong with cops...
只不过其中也有害群之马罢了
Just bad ones.
那是什么? 看啊
What's that? Look.
那里有金属的东西
Something metal right there.
我们找到了 孩子
We got 'em, kid.
这件事结束了 我们找到证据了
It's over. We got the evidence.
我警队的朋友会把Brick和他的朋友抓起来的
My friend on the police force will be able to put Brick and his friends away.
没错 那Andre呢? 他还逍遥法外呢
Yeah, but what about Andre? He's still out there.
Andre没有杀你的哥哥
Andre didn't kill your brother.
现在你又想对付他了?
Now you want to go after him too?
当然 这事他也脱不了干系
Hell, yeah. He's just as to blame.
那然后呢?
Then what, hmm?
对付Andre的头儿... 腐败的警察和政客们
Go after Andre's bosses... The corrupt cops and the politicians
那些默许他们为非作歹的人们?
that let them operate?
除非你把你认为与你哥哥的死有关系的 每个人都毁掉 否则你是不会罢手的
You won't be able to stop until you destroy everyone you blame
可这也不能让他复活
for taking your brother's life. It won't bring him back.
你最后不是进监狱就是横尸街头
You'll just wind up in jail or dead.
你觉得你哥哥想让你这样吗?
Do you think that's what your brother wanted for you?
- 你终于打来了 - 匿名报告 警探
There you are. Anonymous tip just came in, Detective.
找到凶器了 你可以起诉Brick了
Got you the murder weapon. You can go ahead and charge Brick.
这可能有点困难 我10分钟前刚把他放走
It's gonna be kind of difficult. I just released him ten minutes ago.
- Brick被放出去了? - Womack强迫我这么做的
Brick's on the street? Womack forced my hand.
他会向Andre指认Darren的
He'll be able to ID Darren to Andre.
现在你要做的就是别让那孩子露面
All the more reason why you need to get that kid off the street now.
别担心...
Don't worry--
枪和孩子都在我这里
I'll get you the gun, along with the kid.
- Darren - 出什么事了?
- Darren. - What's going on?
Carter...
你该说 "我早就告诉过你了"
You're gonna say, "I told you so."
Finch Darren跑了 可能又去找Brick了
Finch, Darren's run off, probably to go after Brick again.
这次他手里有他们用来杀死他哥哥的枪
And this time he's got the gun they used to kill his brother.
换句话说 让14岁的孩子雇你
In other words, the idea of letting a 14-year-old hire you
- 给他哥哥报仇这主意失败了? - 你能晚点再说我吗
to avenge his brother has backfired? You can lecture me later.
现在我需要你把包给我拿过来
Right now I need you to bring me the bag.
- 哪个包? - 贴着"'B'计划"的那个包
Which bag? The one labeled "plan 'B'".
- 嘿 你需要帮手吗?  - 我不知道 你觉得呢?
Hey. You need backup? I don't know. Do I?
我认为这事和队长让你扔回海里的那条鱼有关系
I figured it might've had something to do with that fish the captain had you throw back in the sea.
可能吧 我得到了一条线报
It might. I got a tip.
想去钓鱼吗?
You want to go fishing?
当然 为毛不去呢?
Yeah, sure, why not?
这就是那孩子?
That's the kid?
Darren 对吧? 没错 我认出你了
Darren, right? Yeah, I recognize you.
我们得谈谈 对吧 你和我?
We got something to talk about, right, you and me?
Plan B
Darren在里面呢
Darren's in there.
放轻松 Finch 里面装的是微创子弹 非致命性武器
Relax, Finch. It's bean-bag rounds, riot ammo.
我告诉过那孩子不许杀人
I told the kid no killing.
我一给你信号 你就去掐断大楼的供电系统
On my signal, you're gonna cut the power to the building.
刚就是我的信号啊 Finch
That was the signal, Finch.
你一个人来这真是勇敢啊 Darren
It's pretty brave of you coming in here like that, Darren.
我明白 我真的明白
I get it. I do.
我的人杀死了你哥哥
My man took someone from you,
所以你来这要取走他的性命
so you're here to take him from me.
所以尽管杀死他吧
So go ahead and shoot him.
我是说 他是那个失手在先的人 是他让我们置于如此田地的
I mean, he's the one that screwed up in the first place, even put us in this situation.
所以你不如帮我个忙
So you're doing me a favor here.
- 喂 Andre... - 你丫闭嘴
- Yo, Andre-- - Shut your mouth.
我知道你拥有
I see you got it in you.
没错 你有这种信念
Yeah, you got that conviction.
这是一种很坚强的品质
It's a hard quality to find around here.
所以你尽管扣动扳机
So you go ahead and pull that trigger.
你应该来给我效力
You should come work for me.
你很年轻 等你到了Brick这个岁数
You're young enough, by the time you Brick's age,
你就能帮我管理这片地盘了 孩子
you'll be running these streets for me, son.
没人敢碰你一根汗毛 你知道为什么吗?
Ain't nobody gonna touch you. You know why?
因为你比他们都要聪明
Because you smarter than the rest.
现在 你一路走到了这里
Now, you made it all the way here.
开枪吧...
Go ahead...
领走你的奖赏
And claim that reward.
领走它吧
Claim it.
拜托 快点啊
Man, come on, come on.
没错 我想到会是这种结果
Yeah, I thought that might happen.
我不怪你 这都怪书店
I don't blame you. I blame the store.
孩子们一天到晚地看那些复仇的故事
Kids spending their days reading these revenge stories,
以为那就是真的
selling it like it's reality.
但你知道漫画书的真相吗?
But you know the thing about comic books?
它们终究不过是漫画
They're just comics.
怎么会这样? 怎么会这样?
What the hell is that? What the hell is that?
走!
Move!
去后面
Go around back.
纽约警察 放下武器
NYPD, drop your weapon.
趴下 孩子!
Get down, kid!
Fusco!
Fusco 你还好吗?
Fusco, you okay?
- 嗯 我还好 - 过来
- Yeah, just peachy. - Come here.
你知道吗? 不管你要说什么 都别说了
You know what? Whatever you got to say, save it.
我已经可以看到我回去以后 桌子上的屁股状蛋糕了
I can already see the ass cake on my desk when I get back.
不 事实上我只是想说声谢谢
No, man, actually, I just wanted to say thank you
谢谢你救了我一命
for saving my life.
不客气
You're welcome, kid.
来吧 我们走 把我从这弄走吧
Come on. Let's go. Get me out of here.
嘿 轻点 行吗?
Hey, take it easy, will you?
- 我还以为你会留下来呢 - 在曼哈顿 你懂的...
Just when I thought you were sticking around. Manhattan, you know...
我就会有点幽闭恐惧的感觉
Got a little claustrophobic.
- 苏丹正好有份工作 - 我很难过你又要离开了
And a job's come up in Sudan. I'll be sorry to lose you again.
那个女人... 我不记得她的名字了
That woman-- I've forgotten her name.
她告诉你你想知道的事情了吗?
Did she tell you what you wanted to know?
Alicia Corwin... 她告诉了我一些事情
Alicia Corwin-- She told me some stuff.
我不知道那是不是我想知道的 你知道 我一直把我父亲当做我的偶像
I don't know if it's what I wanted to know. You know, I had my dad on a pedestal.
爱他也好 恨他也罢 但我一直很崇拜他
Loved him, hated him, but just always admired him.
所以很难想象他不过也是个普通人
It's kind of hard to believe he was just an ordinary guy,
像普通人一样也会犯错误
made mistakes like everybody else.
不管她跟你说了什么 有一件事你应该知道
Well, whatever she told you, there's one thing you should know about him.
不管什么时候 不管什么人问他 他最自豪的成就是什么
Anytime anyone ever asked him what his proudest achievement was,
他都会说是你
he always said that it was you.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 照顾好自己 - 嗯
- Take care of yourself. - Yeah.
Fusco告诉我他们给你找了个收养家庭
You know, Fusco tells me they got a lead on a foster family.
我有家
I had a family.
Darren 我们对发生在我们身上的事无能为力...
Darren, we don't get to choose what happens to us...
但我们可以选择不同的应对方式 我调查过他们
Just what we do about it. I looked into them.
- 他们人不错 - 如果他们对我不好呢?
They're good people. And if they aren't?
那我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
我还是会为你效劳的
I'm, uh, still on the clock.
我想画得更好一些 但是给...
I'm still working on it, but here...
这是给你的
This is yours.
你是这么认为的啊?
Would you look at that?
我一直想要一个好搭档
I always wanted a sidekick.
多谢了
Thanks.
这让我想到...
Which, uh, reminds me...
我找了找人
I pulled some strings.
你可以去读艺术了
You'll be starting at that charter school for the arts.
我的小号
My trumpet.
- 他们那也有绘画课 - 是吗?
They got drawing classes too. Is that right?
记住 抓住机会 等于机会加倍
Remember, opportunities multiply as they're seized.
孙子说的... 没错
Sun Tzu... Right.
嘿 别担心
Hey, don't worry, man.
总有一天 你也会找到一个家的
Someday you'll find a home too.
谢谢
Thanks.
来吧 孩子 他们在屋里等你呢
Come on, kid, they're waiting for you inside.
好的
All right, man.
怎么了 Fusco?
What's up, Fusco?
嘿 我觉得你另一半屁股上
Hey, man, I think you're gonna need a bullet
也应该挨个枪子 就不这么一瘸一拐的了
in that other cheek to even out that limp.
我也很高兴见到你
Good to see you too.
走吧
Come on.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
- 你觉得他会渡过这个难关吗? - 他是个坚强的孩子
Think he'll be all right? He's a tough kid.
我们及时出现是件好事情
It's a good thing we showed up in time, you know.
你跟Carter走得太近了 据我所知 她还在寻找你
You're cutting it awfully close with Carter. She's still looking for you, last I checked.
我之前说过 Carter的事情我来担心
Like I said, you let me worry about Carter.
- 那件事有什么新消息吗? - 有的
Any news on that other thing? Yeah.
他有很多化名 我甚至不知道从哪里着手
He's got so many aliases, I don't even know where to start.
我能查到的最老的一个是Harold Wren
Oldest one I could find is a Harold Wren.
他担任一家保险公司的承销商很多年了
He's an underwriter for an insurance company for a number of years.
在那之前 他是MIT的学生 他们班的尖子
Before that, MIT student, top of his class.
在那里他遇见了那孩子的爸爸...
It was there where he met the kid's dad--
Nathan Ingram
You know, Nathan Ingram.
他是那个前几年被杀死的亿万富豪
He's that billionaire that got killed a couple years back.
Ingram...
和Wren是一个班的同学
Graduated from the same class as Wren.
没错 除了我还多调查了一点
Yeah, except I did a little more digging.
Wren是他在MIT第一年用的名字
Wren was the name he used freshman year at MIT.
那个名字在1976年前没有任何记录
That name doesn't appear on any records before '76,
也就是说Wren也是个假身份
which tells me that Wren was a false identity too.
这个人花了大把的时间去假装别人
This guy spent so much time being someone else,
他可能都不知道自己的本来面目了
he probably doesn't know who he is anymore.
"只有偏执狂才能生存" (Andrew S Grove的一本著作)
"Only the paranoid survive."
你知道的 Lionel...
You know, Lionel...
要不是你曾经犯下的过错 你可以是一个相当好的警察的
You could have been a good cop if not for a few bad choices.
你让我调查你的老板
You got me snooping around your boss,
但我这样做还不对?
but I make bad choices?
人总得有立场
Man has a point.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第14集
Person of Interest S01E14 720p HDTV x264
-= 破烂熊字幕 =-